

MASTER'S CANDIDATE, APPLIED CRYPTOGRAPHY

☐ on request | ☑ elem0@protonmail.com | eleanorm.info | ☐ eleanor-em

Summary_

I am a recently-graduated Master of Science (Computer Science) student at the University of Melbourne, where I researched applied cryptography with Vanessa Teague. I have been a programmer for years, and am passionate about education, security, and privacy. Research interests include zero-knowledge proofs, post-quantum cryptography, and multiparty computation. This year I am due to begin my PhD in theoretical cryptography at ETH Zürich with Ueli Maurer.

Education

University of Melbourne Victoria, Australia

M.Sc. (Computer Science) (with Distinction) 2019-2020

B.Sc. (Mathematical Physics)

Diploma in Informatics

2015-2018

Experience

University of Melbourne Victoria, Australia

RESEARCH ASSISTANT Jul 2019 - Present

Working with Prof. Shanika Karunasekera to develop and deploy RAPID, a large distributed cloud-based system for data collection and analytics.
 The project allows large volumes of data (e.g. from social media) to be categorised by topic and analysed for patterns.

- Responsibilities include finding and fixing issues, as well as developing new features and system monitoring scripts.
- Assisted the security research group with grant applications.
- · Working with Dr Olya Ohrimenko on attacks against differentially private mechanism implementations.

University of Melbourne Victoria, Australia

HEAD TUTOR Jul 2016 - Dec 2020

- Managed the tutoring team for a core subject (Object-Oriented Software Development) with hundreds of students, liaising between students, tutors, and lecturers.
- Developed major assignments for students, including specifications, marking criteria, and testing methodology.
- Delivered one to two lectures per semester on software tools and alternative paradigms while also teaching two to three tutorials per week.
- Tutor for various other subjects including Declarative Programming, Parallel & Multicore Computing, and Research Methods.

CSIRO (Clayton campus) Victoria, Australia

Casual IT Officer Apr 2016-Apr 2017

- · Worked with meterologists to create interactive data visualisation tools for hurricane data.
- Wrote software to process large volumes of unstructured data and extract meaningful information.
- Used augmented reality to work with new data visualisation methods.

Publications

Eleanor McMurtry, Olivier Pereira, Vanessa Teague. When is a test not a proof? ESORICS (2020).

Eleanor McMurtry, Xavier Boyen, Chris Culnane, Kristian Gjøsteen, Thomas Haines, Ronald Rivest, Peter Ryan, Vanessa Teague. **Verifiable Remote Voting with Paper Assurance.** *In Submission.*

Chris Culnane, Eleanor McMurtry, Robert Merkel, Vanessa Teague. Tracing the challenges of COVIDSafe. Blog post.

Honors & Awards_

Best Technology, Codebrew Hackathon
 Student Registration Grant, IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy
 California, U.S.A.

2017 **Excellence in Tutoring Award**, School of Computing & Information Systems, Uni. of Melbourne *Victoria, Australia*

Presentation

CSides Canberra, Australia

ER June 2020

• Presented an introduction to cryptography and formal notions of security.

Speaker July 2020

· Presented an in-depth exploration of the COVIDSafe mobile app, focusing on the root causes of the issues with its application security.

Projects

Cryptid & PaperVote

University of Melbourne 2019-2020

- Cryptid (https://github.com/eleanor-em/cryptid) is a threshold ElGamal implementation in Rust, over Curve25519. It also implements various zero-knowledge proofs, including a shuffle proof based on that in Verificatum.
- PaperVote (https://github.com/eleanor-em/papervote/) is an implementation of a verifiable voting protocol using Cryptid, based around augmenting postal voting techniques.
- This project is related to Master's work and the paper "Verifiable Remote Voting with Paper Assurance".